<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?> 
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xml:lang="en">
 <title type="text">My Blog: My Blog</title>
 <link rel="self" href="http://www.example.com/feeds/all.atom.xml" />
 <link href="http://www.example.com/index.html" />
 <id>urn:http-www-example-com:-index-html</id>
 <updated>2019-09-05T15:08:26Z</updated>
 <entry>
  <title type="text">Cassandra Lab1</title>
  <link rel="alternate" href="http://www.example.com/2019/09/cassandra-lab1.html?utm_source=all&amp;utm_medium=Atom" />
  <id>urn:http-www-example-com:-2019-09-cassandra-lab1-html</id>
  <published>2019-09-05T15:08:26Z</published>
  <updated>2019-09-05T15:08:26Z</updated>
  <author>
   <name>Cassandra Wendlandt</name></author>
  <content type="html">
&lt;p&gt;In this lab we started going over the course outline and basic Linux command lines like creating a directory, removing the directory and editing a text file in a plain text editor like vim. This was a pretty simple task but it was a nice refresher to get back to working with the command line.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Then we started setting up the frog project in order to keep our journal entries. This was a new concept to learn. This was a very interesting new concept to learn as well. The steps were pretty easy to follow which helped a lot. It was a little confusing to start. Starting a blog post was simple but then finding it to edit it was a little confusing. Then trying to have it appear on the blog was a bit tricky but it was a simple error I made. Besides the start I found it pretty simple to use now.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;After the frog project was set up we moved to look at Git. This wasn&amp;rsquo;t that new of an idea as I worked within the past for other classes. The way of accessing it was a new concept. I was not use to working out of the command line to access it. To start we read a section on understanding Git. Then we set up the git repository and added the frog project. Then we pushed the project to get. It was different getting use to working with Linux just from the command line but after a few times it got a lot less confusing.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.example.com/2019/09/cassandra-lab1.html?utm_source=all&amp;amp;utm_medium=Atom"&gt;&lt;em&gt;More&amp;hellip;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt;</content></entry></feed>