<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?> 
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xml:lang="en">
 <title type="text">My Blog: Posts tagged 'Author: Cassandra Wendlandt'</title>
 <link rel="self" href="http://www.example.com/feeds/Author-Cassandra-Wendlandt.atom.xml" />
 <link href="http://www.example.com/tags/Author-Cassandra-Wendlandt.html" />
 <id>urn:http-www-example-com:-tags-Author-Cassandra-Wendlandt-html</id>
 <updated>2019-10-15T13:28:36Z</updated>
 <entry>
  <title type="text">Lab 12</title>
  <link rel="alternate" href="http://www.example.com/2019/10/lab-12.html?utm_source=Author-Cassandra-Wendlandt&amp;utm_medium=Atom" />
  <id>urn:http-www-example-com:-2019-10-lab-12-html</id>
  <published>2019-10-15T13:28:36Z</published>
  <updated>2019-10-15T13:28:36Z</updated>
  <author>
   <name>Cassandra Wendlandt</name></author>
  <content type="html">
&lt;h1 id="what-new-concepts-if-any-did-you-learn-about-in-this-lab"&gt;What new concepts (if any) did you learn about in this lab?&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This lab was mainly about completing the project The Robot from &lt;a href="http://eloquentjavascript.net/07_robot.html"&gt;Chapter 7&lt;/a&gt; of the Eloquent JavaScript. We were introduced to &lt;strong&gt;Spy&lt;/strong&gt; to use it as as tool to intercept calls to &lt;code&gt;console.log&lt;/code&gt; . Spy is to be used when methods are terrible to test because they do not return anything. This allows you to be able to test the source code without actually changing the source code. Spys essentially replaces &lt;code&gt;console.log&lt;/code&gt;. Another new concept was &lt;code&gt;class&lt;/code&gt; in JavaScript. They seem to work very similar was the classes in java which made it easier to understand what is going on.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1 id="what-concepts-are-familiar-from-other-courses-or-from-your-own-knowledge"&gt;What concepts are familiar from other courses or from your own knowledge?&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There was not a lot of concepts that were familiar from other course or from my own knowledge.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1 id="what-new-skills-did-you-practice"&gt;What new skills did you practice?&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I did not practice any new skills. However I did practice writing test cases in jasmine. I did this by having to write the test cases for each method that was added to ensure it worked.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1 id="what-specific-details-did-you-find-surprising-interesting-confusing-difficult-or-otherwise-important"&gt;What specific details did you find surprising, interesting, confusing, difficult, or otherwise important?&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I found the ideas about spy’s to be pretty interesting. I found them to be interesting because it was a different way to test functions that did not return anything. They seem like they would be useful in testing things later on.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1 id="what-explicit-tasks-eg-reading-were-you-given-during-this-lab"&gt;What explicit tasks (e.g. reading) were you given during this lab?&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;First we started with representing a graph. This was done by going to &lt;a href="https://eloquentjavascript.net/07_robot.html#h_UmFK5fYed8"&gt;Meadowfield&lt;/a&gt; and copying the code. Then we created jasmine test cases to test the code that we copied. Then we copy the &lt;code&gt;VillageState&lt;/code&gt; class from &lt;a href="https://eloquentjavascript.net/07_robot.html#h_oekYfM5x02"&gt;Eloquent JavaScript&lt;/a&gt;. Next we created jasmine test cases for the class. In order to do this we took the suggested output from chapter 7 and converted it into jasmine test cases. We had to add some extra cases in order to get full test coverage. Next we moved on to work with Spy’s. We read the &lt;a href="https://jasmine.github.io/tutorials/your_first_suite#section-Spies:_%3Ccode%3EcreateSpy%3C/code%3E"&gt;documentation&lt;/a&gt; on it quickly. We used spy’s to test the random robot section of the code.&lt;/p&gt;</content></entry>
 <entry>
  <title type="text">Lab1</title>
  <link rel="alternate" href="http://www.example.com/2019/09/lab1.html?utm_source=Author-Cassandra-Wendlandt&amp;utm_medium=Atom" />
  <id>urn:http-www-example-com:-2019-09-lab1-html</id>
  <published>2019-09-05T15:00:00Z</published>
  <updated>2019-09-05T15:00:00Z</updated>
  <author>
   <name>Cassandra Wendlandt</name></author>
  <content type="html">
&lt;p&gt;In the lab we started with some Linux command line review. Using the command line to make directory&amp;rsquo;s, open a plain text editor and editing files that way were familiar concepts I learned from a previous coop. It was a good review although because I have not used those commands in a while.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Then we moved on working with Frog. This is new concept for me to learn. It was a very interesting concept for me to learn. At first, I found it was a little confusing but after I got playing around with it and understanding the different parts within the package and the steps we had to do I found it really easy to do.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;After we moved on to getting use to git. This was a new concept for me because I have never really worked with git besides through a web browser. First we started by reading a section from pro git. This section was very helpful for to gain a better understanding of git but reading about the basics. Understanding what the different commands do and understanding what the different messages meant was a little hard but by the end of the lab I had a lot of it understood. A new skill I had a chance to practice was working with git in a command line. I am really glad I got to practice this new skill because I think it will become very helpful in the future. I also think knowing how to be able to access git from the command line is important because it makes working with it so much easier and quicker to get the information you are looking for.&lt;/p&gt;</content></entry></feed>